Guide to the Naomi Shihab Nye Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Works, 1963-2017; 30 boxes
  - Monographs-Edited Poetry, 1982-2010
    - I Feel a Little Jumpy Around You: A Book of Her Poems and His Poems Collected in Pairs, 1999
      - Proof (Box 13, Folder 6)
        Flap, and contributor's notes.
      - "Naomi's Proof", November 28, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Proof, January 2, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        Light edits on introduction.
      - Layout proof (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Cover (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Salting the Ocean: 100 Poems by Young Poets, 2000
      - Art (Box 14, Folder 3)
        25 prints and color photocopies by Ashley Bryan.
    - Is This Forever, Or What?, 2004
      - Uncorrected advanced proof (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Time You Let Me In: 25 Poets Under 25, 2010
      - Contributors (Box 14, Folder 5)
        Poems and bios with Nye annotations.
      - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Bangladesh Section, Poetry International, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Correspondence and poems by Abu Zafar Obaidullah, Farhad Mazhar, Humayun Azad, Humayun Kabir, Mohammad Moniruzzaman, Rafiq Azad, Al Mahmud. Preface and contributor's notes.
  - Monographs-Prose, 1994-2016 and undated
    - Cookbook, unpublished, undated
      - Research (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sitti's Secrets, 1994
      - Early drafts (Box 14, Folder 9)
        Also titled "Connected" and "No War, Please."
      - Drafts (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Benito's Dream Bottle, 1995
      - "Dream Bottle", 1990
        Handmade book
      - "Dream Bottle" (Box 14, Folder 12)
        Short story
      - Layout draft (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Never in a Hurry: Essays on People and Places, 1996
      - Correspondence with editors, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Proof (Box 14, Folder 15)
        273 pages
      - Blurb and promotion (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Habibi, 1997
      - Early notes and fragments (Box 14, Folder 17)
        Annotations by Nye and Duncan.
      - Early draft (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Early draft (Box 14, Folder 19)
        Fragments with notes. Heavily annotated by Duncan.
      - Complete draft (Box 15, Folder 1)
        With notes by Nye and Duncan.
      - "Third send-in" (Box 15, Folder 2)
        Complete draft. Heavily annotated, with correspondence from Virginia.
      - Complete draft (Box 15, Folder 3)
        Heavily annotated.
      - Partial draft, October 29, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Late draft, November 20, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Late draft, clean (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Bound proof, February 24, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Excerpt/review, cover proofs (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Lullaby Raft, 1997
      - Proofs
        With cover and illustrations. Oversized.
    - Baby Radar, 2003
      - Notes and annotated draft (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Draft (Box 16, Folder 5)
        With annotations by Nye and Duncan.
      - Illustrations
        Oversized
    - Going, Going, 2005
      - Notes and research (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Draft and fragments (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - "Draft 1", January 1, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        Includes correspondence to Duncan from Nye.
      - "Draft 2," (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - "Take 6," (Box 16, Folder 10)
        Draft manuscript with notes. Includes correspondence to Duncan from Nye, and annotations by Duncan.
      - Post-publication (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - I'll Ask You Three Times, Are You Ok?, 2007
      - Proof, cover, and review (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - There Is No Long Distance Now: Very Short Stories, 2011
      - Notes (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Draft (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Proof (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - The Turtle of Oman, 2016
      - Notes, research, circa 2008 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Notes, correspondence from Duncan, 2013, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - "Happy House" (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Early drafts (Box 17, Folder 7)
        Some include notes from Virginia Duncan.
      - Draft (Box 17, Folder 8)
        With corrections and annotations by Duncan and Nye.
      - Draft (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Draft (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Proof, June 16, 2014 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Editor Correspondence, 1989-2014
    - November, 1989 - December, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes draft of Connected.
    - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes submissions to and comments on The Tree Is Older Than You Are.
    - 1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Includes draft of Connected and Benito's Dream Bottle
    - 1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Includes draft and notes on contributors for The Tree is Older than You Are "Mexico Book."
    - January - June 1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - July - August 1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - September - December 1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Includes This Tree is Older than you Are (contributors), I Feel a Little Jumpy
    - January - May, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Includes partial draft and proof of I Feel a Little Jumpy, and Duncan's response to Habibi.
    - June - December 1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Includes copyediting and draft of Habibi chapter.
    - January - June 1997 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Includes poems and title for Fuel, and poems for Come with Me.
    - July - December 1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence related to The Space Between Our Footsteps.
    - January - April, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Includes images and draft passages for What Have You Lost?. Includes letter from Ashley Bryan.
    - May 1988 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Includes Salting the Ocean, interfiled with What Have you Lost?. Includes floppy disk.
    - July 1988 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Includes Salting the Ocean title, and What Have you Lost? proof with annotations.
    - August - December, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence related to Salting the Ocean and What Have you Lost?.
    - 1999 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Includes contributor response to The Space Between Our Footsteps, Salting the Ocean introduction
    - 2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Includes Salting the Ocean introduction and reviews, The Space Between Our Footsteps reviews in Arabic.
    - 2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Includes notes from Duncan on Going, Going, draft of "To Any Would-Be Terrorists," and notes from Duncan on 19 Varieties of Gazelle
    - 2002 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - January 2003 - April 2009 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Includes A Maze Me, correspondence with Terre Maher, and Time You Let Me In.
    - March 2010 - March 2017 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Short Stories, circa 1970s - 2010s
    - Ahmad - Cookies (Box 20, Folder 6)
      "Ahmad and Hanna," "Any Idea," "Ashtray," "Beet Cake," "Begonias," "Box," "Bringing in the Sheaves," "Cat Lips," "Camel Like Only Camel," "Coats on the Bed," "The Cookies."
    - Damascus - Fun (Box 20, Folder 7)
      "Damascus Gate," "David Crockett's Other Life," "The Day After the Wedding," "Dignity," "Easter Bonnet," "The Endless Breakfast," "Enigma," "Field Trip," "The Folded Edge of the Bag," "Free Day in Toronto," "Fun."
    - Gentle - Keys (Box 20, Folder 8)
      "The Gentle Women," "Going Away," "Hamadi," "Holiday Greetings," "Hot Dog," "Hum," "Humility," "I Don't Want to Talk About It," "I'm Sorry," "In the Church of Crying Babies," "Jesse and the Supernatural Foods," "Keys."
    - Leaving - Lost (Box 20, Folder 9)
      "Leaving Home," "The Little Boy and the Sun," "Little Dog of Sadness," "Little Nomad," "Local Hospitality," "Long Overdue," "The Losing Book," "Lost Camel at McKenzie Bridge."
    - "Maestro" (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Maintenance" (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Marfa - Mint (Box 21, Folder 1)
      "Marfa Lights," "May We Please See the Arab?," "Mint Snowball."
    - "The Miracle of Typing" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "My Life with Medicine" (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - New - Orange (Box 21, Folder 5)
      "New Man," "Nobody Thinks of Dying in the Middle of the Day," "OK," "On the Front Steps of the Hall Where W.S. Merwin is Reading," "One," "One Moment on Top of the Earth," "One Village," "The Orange, the Fig, the Whisper of Grapes."
    - "Pablo Tamayo" (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Peace - Ruby (Box 21, Folder 7)
      "The Peace Party," "The Peace party," "Popayan Story," "The Rattle of Wheels Toward the Rooms of the New Mothers," "Red Velvet Dress," "Rooster," "Roses for Lubbock," "Ruby."
    - "Shoofly Pie" (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "The Shopper," "Stars" (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Thank You in Arabic" (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Thoreau - Used (Box 21, Folder 11)
      "Thoreau is My Partner," "Three Pokes of a Thistle," "Tomorrow We Smile," "Tonight I Fed the Chickens a Pumpkin Pie and Wrote This," "Trees and Stars and More Trees and More Stars," "Tribute to a Friend," "Tulips," "Unlimited Visibility," "Used Cars on Oahu."
    - Water - Your (Box 21, Folder 12)
      "Water," "We Cannot Have a Couch," "Weather Man," "What is the Dickens?," "A Wild of Sand," "With Three Children, At the River," "The World and All Its Teeth," "You can remember that summer," "Your Buddy is Typing."
  - Essays, circa 1970s - 2010s
    - "Adolph's Store & Cafe" (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - About - Bridging (Box 21, Folder 14)
      "About," "Affirmations of of Loyalty," "All Trekked Out: A Non-Trekkie at a Star Trek Convention," "The Alpine Express," "The American Cultural Center in Dhaka, Bangladesh," "At Once," "Banned Poem (East Jerusalem, 1992)," "Beautiful Strangers," "Before you gobble that dinner," "Blood," "Bread," "Breaking the Sound Barrier," "Bridging the Waters"
    - Cat - Grazing (Box 22, Folder 1)
      "Cat Histories," "Chicken Story," "Christmas in Bethlehem," "The City of Chicago, the Laundry Bag, the Poem," "Connected," "Dec. 22, 1978," "Delicious Rhythms, Enduring Words," "Discovering Ourselves Through Words: Pajamas in the Wind," "Doing What We Can," "Esperanza art offers balanced dialogue, ideas," "Gardening is My Favorite Sport," "Grazing"
    - Hot - Lights (Box 22, Folder 2)
      "Hot Wells Oral Histories Project," "How to Get There," "I couldn't believe my ears," "The Inspiration Article," "Last Day of School," "Letter to the Front," "Lights in the Windows"
    - "Max's Cafe" (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Meander - Reading (Box 22, Folder 4)
      "Meander," "Mixed but Not Mixed-Up," "Neighborhood Quartet in a Minor Key," "Notes on an Uninterrupted Hour's Visit with James Michener, Austin, Texas, May 16, 1995," "Newlyweds hike the Inca Trail," "On Being Asked, 'Are You a Good Mother?'," "On the Brink of War," "On Signing Books," "Open Arms," "Poetry Peddler," "Reading Poetry"
    - "Return Address, Betty J. Stagg" (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Seat - Swimming (Box 22, Folder 6)
      "Seat Mates," "Seeing the Nineties," "Seven Splendid Minutes," "Signs & Apparitions," "A Sliver of Brightness Coming Back," "Statement for the Great Plains Issue," "Stepping back into another time," "Stitches," "Stricken city's tranquility recalled," "The Swimming Lesson"
    - Vacant - Your (Box 22, Folder 8)
      "Vacant Lots," "War Has No Imagination," "We All Walk on Bones," "What Do You Think?" "Why is the Busdriver Mean?" "Wind in a Bucket: Poetry and Energy in Young Lives," "Wolves," "Your Voice is a Ticket!"
    - "Columns" (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Includes comments from the San Antonio Express-News. "Roses for Lubbock," "Liberty Food Store," "Introductions," "Train Station," "Downtown Dwellers," "Kids' Conversations," "Schupp's Woodwork," "Beryl Baird," "Critics"
    - Multiple Essays (Box 22, Folder 10)
      "White Coals," "Broken Clock," "Flashbulb," "Pins," "Speaking Arabic" Photocopied from Michigan Quarterly Review. Later published in Never in a Hurry.
    - Published in newspapers (Box 49, Folder 14)
      "Talk, Talk, Talk," "Henry, I Hardly Knew You," "A few notes on humility," "Fun," "The art of signing your book," "An Old, Painful Story," "Struck Invisible," "Seeing the Nineties," "Neighborhood Quartet," "Texas always remained his own country," "Decisions no piece of cake," "Searching the gutter for shine," "Everybody Knows Something...and The Little Engine That Doesn't Feel Like It," "Generations," "San Antonio: The City of Hearts," Letter from Jerusalem"
    - Oversized (Box 54, Folder 5)
      "A Collection of Poets," "Billboards, sign of times," "In Such Times, Ties Must Bind"
    - Reviews, 1984-1999, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Excerpts and quotes, 2005-2014, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Prose notes and fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Prose fragment, undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
    Oversized, 6 handwritten pages. "When I was in high school."
  - Publications, 1969-2017, undated
    Journals and magazines containing poems or prose by Nye. Also includes poetry edited by Nye and an interview. Incomplete runs of Cedar Rock and Organica, containing poetry and edited poetry. Arranged chronologically.
    - "Ode to a Peach" and others, 1969, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Montage (Robert E. Lee High School Literary Journal)
    - "A No-Poem for Here and Now" and Untitled Poem, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      The Folder
    - "Nostalgia of an 8th Semester Tiger" and others, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      The Mirage (Trinity University Yearbook)
    - "Walking Blanco Road at Midnight", Fall 1975/Spring 1976 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Hawaii Review
    - "You Are Not at Home", 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Texas Portfolio
    - "now is like a cup of hot tea", 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      POWER: Personal Reflections by Youth for Youth
    - "On Country Chickens", Octobers 31, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Loon 7
    - "Basketball with The Swami" and "My Grandmother Has Tattooed Feet", 1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Yellow Brick Road
    - Interview Naomi Shihab conducted with Michael Benedikt, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      Benedikt: A Profile
    - "Worry" and "Music", Spring 1977 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      International Poetry Review
    - "Missing the Boat", 1977 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      The Paris Review
    - "The Girl in the Swimming Pool," "In This House," and "The Music Box", Autumn 1979 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      Shadowgraphs
    - "I Am Traveling", July 1980 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Cellar Door
    - "Packing Lunches for The World", Winter 1980 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Permafrost
    - "My Father and The Fig Tree" and "Grandfather's Heaven", 1982 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      Wrapping the Grapeleaves
    - "At La Palmita, Near the Border" and "From Here to There", 1982 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      River Sedge
    - "Local Hospitality", Nov - Dec 1982 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Stories
    - "Teaching Poetry as A Part of Real Life", March - April 1983 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Teachers and Writers
    - "The House in The Heart" and "Old Iron", Spring/Summer 1983 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      The Chowder Review
    - "So Much Happiness", 1984 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      The International Poetry Forum Collector's Deskbook
    - Quote by Naomi Nye, November 1984 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Event
    - "The Brick," "February" and "Arabic Coffee", Winter 1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Painted Bride Quarterly
    - "The Traveling Onion" and "What Are You Doing For Your Country", 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      The Journal of The English Literature Club
    - "St. Louis" and "The Ambassador", 1985 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Image
    - "Bridging the Waters: An Intercultural Exchange", Fall/Winter 1985-86 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Texas Journal
    - "Dying" and "Leaving Texas", April1986 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "The Use of Fiction" and "The Art of Disappearing", December 1986 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      Literary Cavalcade
    - Guest editor, Poetry Pilot, December 1989 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "David Crockett's Other Life", Summer 1990 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Southwest Review
    - "Maintenance", Spring/Summer 1990 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      The Georgia Review
    - "Newcomers in a Troubled Land", 1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "White Coals," "Broken Clock," "Flashbulb," Pins," and "Speaking Arabic", Fall 1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Michigan Quarterly Review
    - "Double Vision in A New Old World", January 1, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      American Way
    - Booklist, January 15, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Booklist
    - "Christmas in Bethlehem", December/January 1993 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Parenting
    - "Wind in a Bucket: Poetry and Energy in Young Lives", October 1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Communicator
    - "Lights in the Windows", Spring 1995 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      The Alan Review
    - "Wedding Cake" and "Elevator", Summer 1995 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Poetry Kanto
    - Poetry Editor, The Texas Observer, July 28, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "A Few Notes on Humility", August 20, 1995 (Box 33)
      Texas
    - "Valentine for Ernest Mann", 1995 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Bookmarks
    - "Three Pokes of a Thistle", Winter 1995 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - "Every Cat Had a Story", March 1996 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Instructor
    - United States Board on books for young People, Inc, Spring 1996 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - "At Home and A Field", Fall 1996 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Voice
    - "We're Flying!—Life with Poetry", Winter 1996 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      Signal Journal
    - "Delicious rhythms", March/April 1997 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      The Horn Book Magazine
    - "Genetics," "Future," "Public Opinion," "Our Son Swears He Has 102 Gallons of Water in His Body" and "The Esteemed Writer Never Reads Poetry", 1998 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      One Trick Pony
    - "The President and the Poets", June 5, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      The Texas Observer
    - "The Literature of an Examined Life: Naomi Shihab Nye", September 1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Texas Literary Connections
    - "Two Farmers / Al and Caroline" and "From Earth", September 27-December 30, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Transformation
    - "Faces Coming Out of Carnegie Hall", December 1998 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      U.S. Catholic
    - Poetry Editor, The Texas Observer, December 25, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "My First True Love", Spring 1999 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      CBC Features
    - "Fiesta Time", March/April 1999 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Journey
    - "Job," "I Was Thinking of Poems," "Shade", Winter 1999 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Five Points
    - "Our Shared Journey", December 1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      School Library Journal
    - Guest editor, Voices, Spring 2000 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - "The Art of Disappearing", November 2000 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      O, The Oprah Magazine
    - "Dog", 2000-2001 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Natural Selection
    - "Jerusalem", 2001 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      Islamic Studies
    - Poetry Editor,The Texas Observer, November 22, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - "This Crutch That I Love", 2002 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Writers on America
    - "The Day", 2003 (Box 26, Folder 18)
      Mizna
    - "It is Not a Game It Was Never a Game", May/June 2003 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      Speakeasy
    - "Palestine is a Country", Sept/Oct 2003 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Poetry Editor, The Texas Observer, August 13, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - "Fear and Imagination", Fall 2004 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - "Open Arms", Fall 2004 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Divide
    - "Just One Gazelle Would be Fine with Me", 2004 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Charlotte Zolotow Lecture
    - "First Day Without You in 99 Years," "We Are Not Nothing", September 2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Maize
    - "The Sweet Arab, the Generous Arab", Spring 2006 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Jung Society of Atlanta
    - "Red Brocade", 2006 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Knowledge Quest
    - "Savages," "Boat House," "Heat", Fall 2006 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      The Cate Review
    - "For Molly", February 9, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "Kindness", Fall/Winter 2007 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Double Take
    - "Supple Cord," "Commentary", 2008 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Inside Out
    - "Arabic Room," "Hello Palestine," "For Aziz, Who Loved Jerusalem", October 2008 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      The Sun
    - "To All the Palestinians Who Die Before", 2009 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Alhambra Poetry Calendar
    - "The Young Poets of Winnipeg", 2009 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Kansas City Voices
    - "Are We Friends?", December 15, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Voices de la Luna
    - "Boy and Egg", September 2010 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Reader's Digest
    - "A Strange Thing Happened", 2010 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      Dear Frau Bleibtreu, LiteraturRaum
    - "Sphinx", 2010 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - "Spring's Return", 2011 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Poetry at Round Top
    - "Ringing", July 15, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "Violin", August 2011 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Lincoln Center Presents Mostly Mozart
    - "Tell Me", Winter 2011 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      San Pedro River Review
    - "Prayer in My Boot", 2012 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      St. Louis County Attorney's Office 2012 Annual Report
    - "It's Good to Sit Down with a Racist Every Now and Then", Spring 2012 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Harvard Divinity Bulletin
    - "Blood", Spring 2012 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Oregon English Journal
    - "Valentine for Ernest Mann", May 14, 2012 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Scholastic Scope
    - "The Words Under the Words," "Letter from Naomi Shihab Nye," "Kindness", Summer 2012 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      On Second Thought
    - "Famous", Summer 2012 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Summer Theater
    - "The Art of Disappearing," "The Rider", September 2012 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      Remnants
    - Interview, 2013 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Chiu Shui Poetry Quarterly (in Chinese)
    - "To the Crews", 2013 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      Pens Up
    - "Alive", 2013 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - "And Now", Aprilssss 15, 2013 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Two Countries", Oct. 24-Nov. 23, 2013 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Playbill for Lincoln Center Presents: White Light Festival
    - "The Words Under the Words," "Haunted," "What Kind of Fool Am I," and "Hidden", 2014 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      The Art of Change: A Poetry Incubator
    - "Landscapes We Learn to Love," "Business," and "Arabs in Finlan,", Jan-Feb 2014 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      World Literature Today
    - "To Any Would-Be Terrorists," "Lunch in Nablus City Park", Fall 2014 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "How Would the World Be Different?", Sept-Oct, 2014 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Everything Changes the World", November 2014 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Sojourners
    - "We Always Needed You", Winter 2014 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - "San Antonio", 2014-2016 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Love Poems to San Antonio
    - "Mind Lake", 2015 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Pelorus Press
    - "Stars Over Big Bend", May 2015 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      Texas Monthly
    - "Du weißt, wer du bist" (You know who you are) and "Adieu" (Goodby), September 2015 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      Akzente
    - "Gate A-4", June 2016 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      St. Louis County Attorney's Office Annual Report
    - "Hello, Palestine," "At Mother Teresa's", Jan-Feb, 2017 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      Jefferson Journal
    - "Burning the Old Year" 2017 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      Apricity Magazine
    - "Communication Skills," "Shoulders," "Cross That Line", Winter-Spring 2017 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      WisdomWays
    - "April Fools' Day in Ada, Oklahoma," "Torn Map", Spring-Summer 2017 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      Oklahoma Humanities
    - "Famous", undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
      Gannon University 37th Annual English Awards Night
    - Poems, Oversized, Jan/Feb 1986 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      "Rain," Communities. "The Round Window Waits with its Eye Half Open," "Quiet of the Mind," "So There," "Concrete," ¡Tex! "The Traveling Onion," and Interview with Michael and Naomi Shihab Nye, Forum.
    - Poem, Oversized, January 1, 2001 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      "Clean Slate," New York Times
    - Cedar Rock, 1976-1985 (Box 50)
      Poetry quarterly, New Braunfels, Texas, incomplete. Poetry and poetry editing by Nye.